MORGAN CLARKE

Phone: 416-992-5423 **III** Email: morgs99@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/morgandclarke **III** GitHub: github.com/morgs999

Software Developer

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Software, Engineering, and Communications. Extensive experience combining creative solutions with effective communication and organization to keep up in fast-paced work environments, while always keeping the client first.

- Handles stressful situations with the end goal always in mind
- Quickly adaptable to cutting edge technologies
- Approaches each problem with a combination of logical understanding and creative flair

Technical Skills

Frontend: React, Javascript, Typescript, Next.js, Redux, HTML, CSS (Bootstrap, Tailwind, et al.) **Backend:** Node JS, Express JS, Python, Django, C++, GraphQL, REST API's, Authentication

Database: MongoDB (NoSQL), MySQL, PostgreSQL **Mobile Development:** React Native, Swift, Xcode **DevOps:** Github, Gitlab, Webpack, Babel, NPM

Testing: Pytest, Jest, Mocha

Related Experience

Software Developer - Insurasee, Inc.

(March 2024 - July 2024)

Toronto, ON (Remote) - https://insurasee.com

- Small, agile, 2 person software startup team that designed and implemented business plan for printing property reports for climate anxious clientele.
- Personally created and implemented Mongo DB architecture, and back end server and router architecture (NodeJS and Express JS) to effectively handle 1000's of climate model data entries from third party data providers, and push said data through to front end architecture for consumers.
- Built React pages and components that seamlessly synchronized with back end architecture, with a complex, multi-stage order flow system that reduced inefficient web responsiveness.
- Set up Log4JS Error system through entire codebase so that all errors within software was logged for debugging purposes later.
- Technologies Used: MongoDB, React, Javascript, Node JS, Express, Bootstrap, RESTFUL API
- · Libraries Used: Stripe, React PDF, Log4JS, CORS, Axios

Audio Engineer - Self Employed

(2018 - 2024)

New York, NY; Dallas TX; Toronto ON (Hybrid)

- Self-employed and small business owner with dedicated clientele providing professional services in all manner of audio production (recording engineer, audio editor, mixing engineer, and live sound engineer).
- Managed and utilized massive set of software applications, including larger scale (Digital Audio Workstations) and smaller scale (third party plugins), to provide clientele with commercial ready results, often on tight deadlines and with efficient turnaround.
- Began designing and programming custom software applications (audio plugins in C++) to streamline my personal templates of audio production.

• Release of over 1000 podcast episodes for a large list of varied shows and topics across multiple web and app storefronts, and provided consulting services for several startup podcasts.

Communications Coordinator - NYC District Council of Carpenters (2014 - 2018)

New York, NY (In-Person)

- Helped with design and implementation of new website, including utilizing a content management system through Drupal
- Regular website maintenance upon deployment, including user authentication system on back end
- Produced copy for press releases and responses, conference and award speeches, social media, political endorsements, etc.
- Award-winning photography, writing, and newsletter production, wrote long-form and short-form stories for quarterly magazine.

Education

Full Stack Web Development Certificate: University of Toronto, Toronto ON (Completed Feb 2024)
An intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS.

Python Web Developer Micro-Credential: Sheridan College, Mississauga, ON (Completion Nov 2024) Continuing studies certification in Python programming language covering 3 courses: Introduction to Python Programming, Building and Testing Python Applications, and Python Web Development.

Bachelors of Arts, English: University of Oklahoma, Norman, OK
Undergraduate degree focused on Classics: Literature, Philosophy, and History. Member of Pride of Oklahoma
Drumline, Boheme Student Theater Troupe, Sigma Phi Epsilon fraternity.

Software Projects

What's Up Doc? I https://github.com/morgs999/Whats-Up-Doc I whats-up-Doc I <a href="https://github.com/morgs999/What

- A medical patient web application to find doctors, book appointments, and refill prescriptions
- Set up GraphQL server, MongoDB integration, Authentication and Login system, React pages and components
- React JS, GraphQL & Apollo Server, Javascript, Mongo Atlas, Tailwind CSS, PostCSS

Anyway, here's Wonderwall I https://github.com/Levi-Man/Wonderwall I wonderwall-196032f35f7e.herokuapp.com

- A music lookup application that allows users to create profiles, save their favourites, and lookup relevant music
- Designed main layout, incorporated MusicBrainz API requests, and integrated 3rd party NPM library to return Billboard Chart songs
- Node JS, Express JS, MySQL, Handlebars, Bootstrap CSS

Leftover Lover I https://github.com/DamirFM/leftover I damirfm.github.io/leftover/

- A web application that lets users look up a leftover ingredient they have and match that to recipes and Youtube results to help them decide what to make for dinner
- Designed main layout, helped integrate Youtube API results, helped with MealDB API requests
- Node JS, RESTFUL API's, Bulma CSS, HTML